Finding Aid for Alpheus Felch papers 1817-1896
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Personal Files
  - Felch Family
    - Sketches of family members by Lillian Felch, 1934 (Box 4)
  - Lawrence Family
    - Sketches of family members, circa 1933-1934 (Box 4)
  - Genealogies
    - Felch and Lawrence families (Box 4)
    - Lougee family (Box 4)
  - Student papers
    - General (Box 4)
    - Bowdoin College (Box 4)
    - Poetry, circa 1820s (Box 4)
    - Manuscript map of the United States drawn while student at Bowdoin College, 1 items in oversize folder (Box 4)
  - Deeds, 1836-1854; 1872; undated (Box 4)
  - Mortgages (Box 4)
  - Speeches, 5 folders (Box 4)
- U.S. Commission to Settle Private Land Claims in California, 1853-1856
  The U.S. Commission to Settle Private Land Claims in California (1853-1856) series consists of correspondence and legal briefs on the issue of adjusting Spanish and Mexican land claims. Of note are the six bound volumes (oversized) containing Felch's opinions on the California cases and the final decisions of the commission.
  - Records (Box 5)
    - circa 1853-1856, 5 folders (Box 5)
    - July 1853-August 1853 (Box 5)
    - September 1853-December 1853 (Box 5)
    - January 1854-August 1854 (Box 5)
    - September 1854-December 1854 (Box 5)
    - January 1855-March 1855 (Box 5)
  - Legal briefs
    - U.S. v. Joseph S. Alemany, circa 1852 (Box 5)
    - U.S. v. Andres Castellaro, circa 1853 (Box 5)
    - U.S. v. John Sutter, et al. (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1851-1860 (Box 5)
    - List of cases adjudicated (Box 5)
    - San Francisco v. U.S., 1854 (Box 5)
    - Cervantes v. U.S. (Supreme Court decision), 1853 (Box 5)
  - Final report, March 3, 1856 (Box 5)
  - Court calendar; docket index; financial records, 1851-1855 (Box 5)
  - Register of the Governor of California, Specifying Grants made of lands with dates, 7 pages (Box 5)
    (actually a chronology of governors and political leaders of California, 1769-1846)
  - Decrees under which the California Territory was governed, 1812-1813 (Box 5)
    (photocopies; ca. 50 pp.)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Index to cases (missing case nos. 501, 463, 433) (Volume 1)
  - Opinions (Volume 2)
  - Opinions (Volume 3)
    (continued)
  - Opinions (Volume 4)
  - Decisions (Volume 5)
  - Decisions (Volume 6)
- Miscellaneous
  The Miscellaneous series includes bills and receipts, bank statements, various legal papers, lists, writings, and clippings.
  - Bank statements (Huron River Bank and Bank of Ypsilanti), 1838 (Box 6)
  - Legal brief: People v. The Regents of the University of Michigan (Box 6)
    (printed version of brief also available in print collection of the library)
  - Legal papers, 1838-1842 (Box 6)
  - Louisiana and Michigan survey bills, 1848-1850 (Box 6)
  - Membership lists (Box 6)
  - Ninetieth birthday celebration, 1894 (Box 6)
  - Personal portfolio (Box 6)
  - Sketchbook, undated (Box 6)
  - Will, 1896 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous writings, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Bills and receipts (Box 6)
  - Unidentified and undated (Box 6)
  - Clippings (Box 6)
- Photographs
  The Photograph series contains portraits of Alpheus Felch, his family, friends, and contemporaries.
  - Classmates (classes of 1867 and 1868) (Box 6)
    [see also outsize unbound material]
  - Civil War portraits (Box 6)
  - Cole family (Box 6)
  - Delta Kappa Epsilon (Box 6)
    (oversize photo located in Ac folder)
  - Homes, cemeteries (Box 6)
  - Individuals, identified (Box 6)
  - Individuals, unidentified (Box 6)
  - Lawrence family of Monroe, Michigan (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Portraits, engraved (Box 6)
  - Portraits, photographic (Box 6)